Daniel Nieto González

Portfolio https://nietodaniel.github.io

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/nietodaniel-apps/

Cel <u>+57 3219752073</u>

Email d-nieto@javeriana.edu.co

Location • Colombia / Remote work

Software architect in formation. Data scientist, full stack software developer (>5 years of experience, 864 hours of certified academic training) and entrepreneur in services & technologies for biomedical researchers (www.digitalmedtools.com), 29 years. Experience in projects using agile methodologies (SCRUM). My multidisciplinary experience, flexibility, search of personal &professional growth, and calmness under pressure allow me to solve any situation without problems.

- Full stack developer: Frontend, backend & data science developer. Experience using agile methodologies: SCRUM.
- **Software Architect:** Proficient in identifying efficient software architecture patterns to address the incoming challenges. Formation in ADD, ATAM, 4+1 view, among other methodologies.
- Data Science Engineer: data science and machine learning projects under CRISP-DM, applying software architecture concepts to efficiently address the situation.
- Machine Learning: Data processing, applying supervised and unsupervised algorithms for classification and regression. Experience with deep learning, deep reinforcement learning, neural networks, among others
- Front-End developer: React, Angular, Vanilla Javascript, Jquery, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, HTML, Blade templates (Laravel), Redux, ExpressJS
- Back-End developer: Django, Laravel/Lumen. Basic knowledge: NodeJS, C#, Databases (MySQL, Oracle)
- **DevOps Engineer**: App deployment. Heroku, IIS, Github Pages
- Data Science developer: Python, R, R packages, Azure ML studio, API integrations, SQL queries
- Statistical & research advisor: Consultant in biostatistics, scientific research, redaction, etc.
- Data analyst: Proficient in basic & inferential statistics, use of statistical software (minitab, stata, R, Excel, etc.). Data visualization: Mathplotlib (python), R, PowerBI, tableau
- **Language**: Spanish: native. English: listening, reading, writing (*Advanced*). Speaking (*Basic*)

Education

• Master of systems engineering (*Post-Graduate, currently studying*): Grade: 4,46. Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, Bogotá. Formation in Machine learning and Software Architecture: 864 certified academic hours:

Advanced topics in analytics (192 h). Grade: 5,0 Methods and applications in analytics II (192 h). Grade: 4,5 **Design and evaluation of software architecture** (192 h). Grade: 4,0. Data management (96 h). Grade: 4,9 Business intelligence (192 h). Grade: 4,4. Multiagent systems (192 h). Grade: 4,3

• Biologist (Pre-Graduate): Grade: 4,05. Universidad del Valle, Cali

Work experience (>5 years)

Software developer (>3 Years)

Software Developer in Vision & Marketing https://www.paho.org/bireme/, ENE 2021 – PRESENT Construction of a platform for finding jobs and easing the process of candidate selection for business. (Supervisor: Lina Obando). Technologies: Angular, React, Django, Python, Github, IIS (Deployment)

Contractor in BIREME/OPS/PAHO https://www.paho.org/bireme/, FEB 2019 - NOV 2019

Planning, design & development of a software aimed to ease the search of academic papers using the PICO (Patient, Intervention, Comparison, Outcome) methodology. (Supervisor: Renato Murasaki). *Technologies*: Laravel, PHP, Github

Software Developer & CEO (Independent) in Digital MedTools (www.digitalmedtools.com). JUN 2018 – PRESENT Entrepreneur in services for biomedical researcher. See references: Lina María Villegas, Luis Gabriel Parra, Lyda Osorio. Technologies: Laravel, Django, Python, R, Angular, React, C#, .net core, NodeJS, MySQL, Heroku, Github

Data scientist (>5 years)

Data scientist in Alianza Caoba http://alianzacaoba.co/, AUG 2020 – OCT 2020.

Prediction of children under state of malnutrition using different algorithms of machine learning. Project "Analítica de datos para estimar el riesgo de desnutrición de niños y niñas en Colombia bajo Covid-2019", Manos en la Data, CAF (Supervisor: Julio Carreño). Technologies: Azure ML Studio, Python, R, Stata, PowerBI

Data analyst in SIT CONSULTING https://sitconsulting.com.co/, JAN 2018 – SEP 2018.

Data analyst and statistical advisor for projects of biomedical researchers (Supervisor: Lina María Villegas).

Technologies: Python, R, SQL

Statistical consultant, data analyst (Independent) JAN 2016 – DIC 2020.

See References: Julio Ernesto Carreño, Lina María Villegas, Luis Gabriel Parra. Technologies: Python, R, SQL, Javascript

R Package Developer (Independent) OCT 2020 – PRESENT.

R package developer for data science, machine learning and biomedical research (https://github.com/nietodaniel). My packages: LargeDataExplorer (https://github.com/nietodaniel/LargeDataExplorer):

Public repositories

Portfolio (React): My work portfolio. Built in react. Available: https://github.com/nietodaniel/nietodaniel.github.io

LargeDataExplorer (**R**): Powerful package to clean and re-format very large datasets after classifying its variables by their usefulness for machine learning. Available: https://github.com/nietodaniel/largedataexplorer

PICOSearcher (PHP-Laravel): PICO (Patient, Intervention, Comparison, Outcome) searcher built for the latin american branch of the World Health Organization (WHO): BIREME/OPS/PAHO, Available: https://github.com/bireme/PICO-BackEnd

Análisis Exploratorio de Productos en Mercados (Python): Analysis of the sell statistics in Colombian supermarkets using Python seeking to identify the 20 best product sectors for entrepreneurship. Available: https://www.kaggle.com/nietodaniel/an-lisis-exploratorio-de-productos-en-mercados

Research experience

- Grupo de Epidemiología y salud poblacional (GESP), 2018. Project Neurovirus Emergentes de las Américas (NEAS)
- Design √ of two digital solutions built in Excel and Visual Basic, for biomedic research: RevEasy: Medical Systematic Searches Optimizer and Screening Tool

Awards

- Incentive for academic excellence. Biology undergraduate program. Universidad del Valle. Semesters 1, 3 and 9.
- Best ICFES. Colegio Lacordaire, Cali. Grade 11 (2009).

References (Contact info only available for Human Resources of interested companies)

Julio Ernesto Carreño Vargas (<u>LinkedIn</u>). Appointed professor. Department of Systems Engineering. Pontificia Universidad Javeriana.

Luis Gabriel Parra Lara (LinkedIn). Medical Degree, Universidad del Valle. Junior scientific researcher, Colciencias.

Lina María Villegas (LinkedIn). MSc Biomedic Sciences. CEO. SIT Consulting Colombia.

Lyda Elena Osorio (LinkedIn). PhD Epidemiology. Appointed professor. Leader of Grupo de Epidemiología y Salud Poblacional (GESP). Universidad del Valle.

Marvin Cely (LinkedIn). Web UI developer, Globant. Master's student of systems and computing engineering.

Abraham Montes Humanez (<u>LinkedIn</u>). Drilling Engineer, Ecopetrol. Master's student of systems and computing engineering.

Contact

Contact me for more information and if you want access to the full version of my curriculum Vitae: +57 3219752073

